[{"id": "5ccf7b08b37b32637bdc44c3", "question": "In what year was the first opera created?", "answer": "1597", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133923b", "question": "What is the nickname of Andy's prison buddy in \"The Shawshank Redemption\"?", "answer": "Red", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff51739ff04d658268c92fa", "question": "The bottom of King Tutankhamun's sandals depicted what?", "answer": "His enemies -- A painting of his enemies was found on the soles, which allowed him to trample on his enemies for all of eternity.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fed265aec223966ae8f8909", "question": "In early 2019, Ariana Grande held the top three spots on the Billboard Hot 100. Who is the only other artist(s) to have achieved this feat prior to her?", "answer": "The Beatles", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fefc45d6ce05a3942286f31", "question": "The pop band, The Bangles, would like for their fans to walk like what?", "answer": "An Egyptian", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff0b0bfe662d71a53650fcb", "question": "In Harry Potter's world, what is the first name of Andromeda Tonks daughter?", "answer": "Andromeda Tonks daughter and only child is Nymphadora Tonks.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7d0", "question": "By area, what is the smallest of the Great Lakes?", "answer": "Lake Ontario", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f6b", "question": "What vehicle was driven by Michael Knight?", "answer": "KITT", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c252", "question": "What is 11 squared?", "answer": "121", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388b8", "question": "In the children's toe-counting rhyme, what did the third little piggy have?", "answer": "Roast Beef", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5922067da4edfd43a087adee", "question": "In which Arthur Miller play does Willy Loman feature?", "answer": "Death of a Salesman", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b8d", "question": "What love\u00adstruck Warner Brothers cartoon character often chased a black cat named Penelope?", "answer": "Pepe Le Pew", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58f1684df7c52aae91cc07c5", "question": "Selaphobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Light flashes", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd6631da5bfecdd737e084c", "question": "What was the final battle of the Vietnam War?", "answer": "The Mayaguez Incident", "category": "history"}, {"id": "594d077d1a1c922dd1ac64b9", "question": "What term is used for the speed at which a piece of music is played?", "answer": "Tempo", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59ae93e4574a5ce6b56b8240", "question": "Who's the lead singer of the band \"Simply Red\"?", "answer": "Mick Hucknall", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339286", "question": "Who is the only player in season 14 of the TV show \"Big Brother\" to be in the house but not have a key?", "answer": "Jodi", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7a6", "question": "What color is the supposedly cursed Hope Diamond?", "answer": "Blue", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad04", "question": "What is a four letter Gaelic name for Scotland?", "answer": "Alba", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59636e3e967692ea851899b2", "question": "What band released their 10th studio album under the name \"Back to Us\"?", "answer": "Rascal Flatts'", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe1f1cb145fb29466707394", "question": "What British automobile company made a car called the Super Snipe?", "answer": "Humber", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c97c", "question": "What constellation is the North Star located in?", "answer": "Ursa Minor", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca30", "question": "Eczema affects which part of the body?", "answer": "Skin", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff516dcff04d658268c92f6", "question": "Which organ was typically left in the body of mummies?", "answer": "Heart", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4d9", "question": "What fruit comes in Bing and Rainier variety?", "answer": "Cherries", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b866", "question": "What chess piece makes an L-shaped move?", "answer": "Knight", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6014c544fbde8045e48466aa", "question": "What is the dugong's (sea cow) closest land relative?", "answer": "Elephant \u2010- Like elephants, males can grow tusks when they reach maturity.  Females can grow tusks, too, if they live long enough.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4ee", "question": "What two pieces are moved in chess's castling maneuver?", "answer": "The king and rook", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a9c", "question": "According to one popular interpretation, what does \"Pinocchio\" mean in Italian?", "answer": "Pine eyes", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5a9e94627ccba3ffe45786d3", "question": "What element has the atomic number 98?", "answer": "Californium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ffa52a7c73aa70ea0b70b1c", "question": "Frankenmuth, a U.S. city nicknamed \"Little Bavaria\", is located in what state?", "answer": "Michigan (It is a German-style town in Saginaw County. It is well known for its hotels and old-style German buildings.)", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c1b", "question": "SpongeBob SquarePants lives in a house shaped like what?", "answer": "Pineapple", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c904", "question": "What is Infantile Paralysis more commonly known as?", "answer": "Polio", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a148", "question": "In the TV series \"The Dukes of Hazzard\", what was painted on the top of their car?", "answer": "Confederate flag", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea3e4eff048f679a45ab59", "question": "What is a plant with no internal system of tube like structures called?", "answer": "Nonvascular Plant", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fac", "question": "What TV title character lived at 485 Mapleton Drive, Mayfield?", "answer": "Beaver Cleaver", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e87", "question": "What future celebrity made an appearance as Opie in \"Andy Griffith\"?", "answer": "Ron Howard", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe3783c0ada16518afdc050", "question": "What was the first Christmas song to focus on Santa Claus?", "answer": "\"Up on the Housetop\"", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9fb", "question": "Marbella is a resort on which SpanIsh coast?", "answer": "Costa del Sol", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c52c", "question": "\"Mach One\" refers to the speed of what?", "answer": "Sound", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca4e", "question": "What is Frank Whittle credited with inventing?", "answer": "Turbojet engine", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fdabd760b8cce1e6fda7063", "question": "What meat is the primary ingredient in Booyah, a thick stew?", "answer": "Chicken", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9a5", "question": "What is the Latin word for poison?", "answer": "Virus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe9f5a4ff048f679a45aad7", "question": "Which of your organs can regenerate itself up to 60%?", "answer": "Liver", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c01e", "question": "Who invented basketball?", "answer": "James Naismith", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffa3b43c73aa70ea0b70ae6", "question": "What is the oldest city in India?", "answer": "Varanasi", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58f16810f7c52aae91cc07c1", "question": "Which opera singer was known as \"La Stupenda\"?", "answer": "Joan Sutherland", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b99d", "question": "Which US state's two letter postal abbreviation is \"HI\"?", "answer": "Hawaii", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5e5f116ed274615ecf514539", "question": "What is the name of Olive Oyl\u2019s sister-in-law?", "answer": "Cylinda Oyl", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b394", "question": "Which Apollo mission carried Neil Armstrong and his team to the Moon?\u00a0", "answer": "Apollo 11", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59067f74ff9c0647b50a8084", "question": "On what date did the 2016 Dyn Cyberattack take place, rendering some of the largest Internet services unusable for several hours?", "answer": "October 21, 2016", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59067b9aff9c0647b50a8066", "question": "What smartglasses were you able to purchase on November 10 2016, from a proprietary vending machine?", "answer": "Spectacles", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b425", "question": "Who was the first thoroughbred horse to win one million dollars?", "answer": "Citation", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59068295ff9c0647b50a809e", "question": "On what streaming platform was Kanye West\u2019s \"The Life of Pablo\" album launched?", "answer": "Tidal", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c854", "question": "What nation is home to the Komodo dragon?", "answer": "Indonesia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339467", "question": "How many \"precogs\" were there in the pre-crime unit in the 2002 movie \"Minority Report\"?", "answer": "Three", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a4a959d61d1b4d384d5d67b", "question": "\"White Room\" was a hit off which Cream album?", "answer": "Wheels of Fire", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe526171bf59ab7d2e380f4", "question": "As of 2020, what was the top selling beer in the world?", "answer": "Snow", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600f749ea9e54d890926f6fb", "question": "Georgia, it\u2019s illegal to eat what with a fork?", "answer": "Fried chicken", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388eb", "question": "What is the dot in the \"i\" called?", "answer": "A tittle", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b21d", "question": "What city was Martin Luther King, Jr. killed in?", "answer": "Memphis", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2d6", "question": "What year saw the release of the first \"Planet of the Apes\" film?", "answer": "1968", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba6d", "question": "What is known as Ireland's \"kissing rock\"?", "answer": "The Blarney Stone", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cc4", "question": "Who painted the ceiling of the Sistine Chapel?", "answer": "Michelangelo", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59f9b9cb364247bf200fb891", "question": "Who is credited with designing the icon look of the Morris Mini-Minor?", "answer": "Alec Issigonis", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af19", "question": "What did the Pony Express transport to California?", "answer": "Mail", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b756", "question": "What team did basketball star Larry Bird play 13 seasons for?", "answer": "Boston Celtics", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a838", "question": "What Ivy League university is located in Ithaca, NY?", "answer": "Cornell", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbec", "question": "What year saw Jean Paul Gaultier's first individual collection for men?", "answer": "1983", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bba1", "question": "What is the name for the fingers of a fork?", "answer": "Tines", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6010c9a30775fa611bce67ed", "question": "What body part do dentils resemble in architecture?", "answer": "Teeth -- A feature of Classical architecture that gives a sense of Greek Revival style. It has the same Latin root as dental.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fdff6ab1cf6db9ac4808cf0", "question": "Where is the longest freshwater beach in the world?", "answer": "Canada", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c03", "question": "Marvin Gaye started singing in the late 1950's as a member of what group?", "answer": "The Moonglows", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9ce", "question": "What is the sternum more commonly known as?", "answer": "Breastbone", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cd5", "question": "What is the surname of Sesame Street's The Count?", "answer": "Von Count", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c562", "question": "In radio, what does AM stand for?", "answer": "Amplitude Modulation", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391b1", "question": "Who played the female lead role in the 2007 movie \"Stardust\"?", "answer": "Claire Danes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac94", "question": "Which Soviet leader approved the building of the Berlin Wall?", "answer": "Nikita Khrushchev", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfc4", "question": "What does \"Flotsam\" describe?", "answer": "Floating wreckage of a ship", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6015e7f1fe83fe1f2a824bd7", "question": "When did the Peasants Revolt take place?", "answer": "1381", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c30", "question": "What is the setting for most of John Steinbeck's novels?", "answer": "Rural farms", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5f95a9e555722f97b22684d1", "question": "What was the last movie Walt Disney was able to work on before he died?", "answer": "The Jungle Book", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a3c8319039f3d7859290ff7", "question": "In the TV Show \"Bonanza\", what was Ben Cartwright\u2019s profession prior to moving to Nevada and buying the Ponderosa?", "answer": "Ship\u2019s chandler", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2e1", "question": "Who sent the 1884 cable that said \"I will not accept if nominated and will not serve if elected\"?", "answer": "William Tecumseh Sherman", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5afad941430e050a5df0d114", "question": "According to most sources, where is the world\u2019s tallest unclimbed unclimable mountain?", "answer": "Bhutan/China", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e25", "question": "What 1904 play was subtitled \"The Boy Who Wouldn't Grow Up\"?", "answer": "Peter Pan", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5febd3b97e83c707845b2154", "question": "How many noble houses of Westeros are there in \"Game of Thrones\"?", "answer": "Nine (Arryn, Baratheon, Greyjoy, Lannister, Martell, Stark, Targaryen, Tully and Tyrell)", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339364", "question": "What was Mary's last name on \"The Mary Tyler Moore Show\"?", "answer": "Richards", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fa1", "question": "Rex Stout created what private eye?", "answer": "Nero Wolfe", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe1f378145fb2946670739a", "question": "What cheese is traditionally used on a Reuben sandwich?", "answer": "Swiss", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a165", "question": "Who sings \"Sweet Home Alabama\"?", "answer": "Lynyrd Skynyrd", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe93d426bd93ce3a4e5f6b2", "question": "What two elements do all silicate minerals contain?", "answer": "Silicon and oxygen", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a97b", "question": "What nation's legislative body is named The Kuvendi?", "answer": "Albania", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58c89d5b011619dd6d415485", "question": "In what season of South Park did the boys claim that Butters wrote the book \"Scrotie McBoogerballs\"?", "answer": "Season 14", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339710", "question": "Who played the role of Moses in the 1950s movie \"The Ten Commandments\"?", "answer": "Charlton Heston", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b3231a6bf195a31e15d7386", "question": "Who shared the 1978 Nobel Peace Prize with Menachem Begin?", "answer": "Mohamed Anwar Al-Sadat", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395ea", "question": "In The Simpsons, who said: \" Good evening, everyone, and welcome to a wonderful evening of theater and picking up after yourselves", "answer": "Principal Skinner", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5c0", "question": "As what type of beans are chickpeas also known as?", "answer": "Garbanzo", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a6", "question": "What movie starred Mel Gibson as William Wallace?", "answer": "Braveheart", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5909cbb9bb53d1af658864da", "question": "Which artist recorded the Christmas song \"Run Rudolph Run\" in 1958?", "answer": "Chuck Berry", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59f9b818364247bf200fb87b", "question": "Which game was the first to require installation of the Steam client to play?", "answer": "Half-Life 2", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b834", "question": "How many times are Mexican refried beans fried?", "answer": "Once", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6a6", "question": "Apple's CEO Steve Jobs was known for wearing what color turtleneck?", "answer": "Black", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a9", "question": "Who voices the character of scientist and inventor Professor John I.Q. Nerdelbaum Frink Jr. on \"The Simpsons\"?", "answer": "Hank Azaria", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59067df9ff9c0647b50a8076", "question": "What is the more common name for the Bigelow Expandable Activity Module that was added to the International Space Station in 2016?", "answer": "BEAM", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca2f", "question": "Laetrile is most often associated with the pit of which fruit?", "answer": "Apricot", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339939", "question": "What legendary record label was founded by Sam Phillips in 1952?", "answer": "Sun Records", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "592eace4f83302ff91e46474", "question": "In which sport might you see a \"Crucifix\" being performed?", "answer": "Gynmastics", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5e1", "question": "What type of a drum has vibrating wires across its bottom?", "answer": "Snare drum", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c68b", "question": "What colorless, odorless gas glows orange\u00ad-red when electricity is discharged  through it?", "answer": "Neon", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e16", "question": "At the end of \"The Da Vinci Code\", the Holy Grail is revealed to be buried at what popular spot?", "answer": "The Louvre Museum", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f18", "question": "Who has been played in a movie by both Kirk Douglas and Tim Roth?", "answer": "Vincent van Gogh", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0f4", "question": "Who had a hit with the song and album \"Sweet Dreams (Are Made Of This)\"?", "answer": "Eurythmics", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5eb737c95e259d786908732c", "question": "Who was the Bolshevik leader that was exiled by Joseph Stalin after Vladimir Lenin\u2019s death?", "answer": "Leon Trotsky", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fdffbb61cf6db9ac4808cf7", "question": "What's the oldest university in England?", "answer": "Oxford University", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cc1", "question": "What band's Greatest Hits album set a US record by going 29 times platinum?", "answer": "Eagles'", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5a3", "question": "Who was the 1994 Fifa World Cup winner?", "answer": "Brazil", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a814", "question": "In what county is Chicago, Illinois located?", "answer": "Cook County", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388ed", "question": "What Harry Potter character has the patronus of a hare/bunny?", "answer": "Luna Lovegood", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1c5", "question": "Who had a No.1 hit song in 1998 with \"C'est la Vie\"?", "answer": "B*Witched", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd04", "question": "In British English, what is the two-initial term for a resume?", "answer": "CV", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e1", "question": "What is the name of the first book in the \"Bourne Trilogy\"?", "answer": "The Bourne Identity", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59f9b7f6364247bf200fb879", "question": "Which Russian chemist created the modern periodic table?", "answer": "Dmitri Mendeleev", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a397", "question": "What is \"The Windy City\"?", "answer": "Chicago", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a141", "question": "Rod Stewart's second album was called after which alley?", "answer": "Gasoline Alley", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea455dff048f679a45ab93", "question": "What South American mammal resembles a small llama?", "answer": "Alpaca", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2ce", "question": "Who played the role of Dudley in the 1947 film \"The Bishop's Wife\"?", "answer": "Cary Grant", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59e80433de59ea584496fea3", "question": "Who wrote the 1956 novel \"The Hundred and One Dalmatians\"?", "answer": "Dodie Smith", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59db77bc0ab2c8f322317fee", "question": "Which holiday did Canada Day replace in 1982?", "answer": "Dominion Day", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59db751e0ab2c8f322317fe4", "question": "Peridot is the birthstone for which month?", "answer": "August", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff51383ff04d658268c92dc", "question": "Which war was ended by the 1763 Treaty of Paris?", "answer": "The signing of the treaty formally ended the Seven Years' War, also known as the French and Indian War.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58dba522874c93a3298b214d", "question": "What country is credited with inventing the modern, self-igniting match?", "answer": "France", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd6a1a26c0f9723ab15cb3c", "question": "What was the first major battle of the American Civil War?", "answer": "Battle of Bull Run", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a926", "question": "What city is threatened by the effects of acqua alta?", "answer": "Venice", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133982b", "question": "What puppeteer created Kermit the Frog and Miss Piggy?", "answer": "Jim Henson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac2c", "question": "What line divided the North and South in the U.S. Civil War?", "answer": "The Mason-Dixon line", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca52", "question": "What is the more common name for the fruit \"Citrus maxima\"?", "answer": "Pomelo", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338984", "question": "Which influential French novelist was a close friend of Paul Cezanne?", "answer": "Emile Zola", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fdff56e1cf6db9ac4808cea", "question": "Where is the mythological birthplace of the Incas?", "answer": "Isla del Sol, Bolivia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397ce", "question": "What TV show began with the words \"Space, the final frontier\"?", "answer": "Star Trek", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c873", "question": "A tetragon is geometric shape that has how many sides?", "answer": "Four", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe8ac0f01dd7bf43be5e769", "question": "Which is the main substance used to make a crayon?", "answer": "Wax", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b801", "question": "How old is a Jewish boy who has a bar mitzvah?", "answer": "13", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59da1b9ff6756c9b30ba14fb", "question": "Kiev is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Ukraine", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a766", "question": "In which US state is Oral Roberts University located?", "answer": "Oklahoma", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe76f73eec85e375820b2ea", "question": "What is the only walled city north of Mexico?", "answer": "Quebec City, Quebec, Canada", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ffa3823c73aa70ea0b70acf", "question": "What mode of transportation is Missouri named for?", "answer": "Canoe (An Illinois tribe's phrase for the area's people, \"ouemessourita,\" translates to \u201cwooden canoe people\".)", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133921d", "question": "In which movie does Hugh Grant play a London bookshop owner?", "answer": "Notting Hill", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58b0e93c964118b2bb3809cb", "question": "St. Dwynwen is the patron saint of lovers in which European country?", "answer": "Wales", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe8a93801dd7bf43be5e74a", "question": "Which animal symbolizes good luck in Europe?", "answer": "Ladybug", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59008bc9cf842fa4c4ba969a", "question": "In which Verdi opera does Violetta sing \"Sempre libera\"?", "answer": "La Traviata", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5db03f91aa1c9af2684d79a7", "question": "Which college did Bill Gates drop out from?", "answer": "Harvard", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af94", "question": "Who popularized the Christmas tree in England in the 19th century?", "answer": "Prince Albert", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c74d", "question": "In 1993, what name did Intel give to its new 80586 line of chips?", "answer": "Pentium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6d9", "question": "What body of water separates Alaska from Russia?", "answer": "Bering Strait", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe76e2deec85e375820b2db", "question": "Where did bungee jumping originate?", "answer": "Vanuatu", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa96", "question": "In what country is Thunder Bay?", "answer": "Canada", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe73894eec85e375820b264", "question": "What is the driest continent?", "answer": "Antarctica", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ec0", "question": "\"The Da Vinci Code\" repeats the myth that the glass pyramid in front of the Louvre consists of how many panes?", "answer": "666", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339207", "question": "What Scottish city is the setting for \"Trainspotting\" according to the plot?", "answer": "Edinburgh", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a06", "question": "Who was the lead singer of the band Soundgarden?", "answer": "Chris Cornell", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa90", "question": "Roseau is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Dominica", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb5f", "question": "What coastal Atlantic US state has \"The Shag\" as their official state dance?", "answer": "South Carolina", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59071ec93745b36be73039e5", "question": "In the \"Revival\" comic book series, what is the family name of the brothers who try to sell parts of the revivers?", "answer": "Check", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bca8", "question": "Who kicked last-second field goals to win two different Super Bowls?", "answer": "Adam Vinateri", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acab", "question": "What month in 1912 saw the Titanic go down?", "answer": "April", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba24", "question": "How many World Professional Snooker championships did Joe Davis win?", "answer": "15", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339925", "question": "What singing duo originally billed themselves as \"Caesar and Cleo\"?", "answer": "Sonny & Cher", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b471", "question": "Which UK politician was given the nickname Tarzan?", "answer": "Michael Heseltine", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58dba51e874c93a3298b214c", "question": "What country is credited with inventing the modern, self-igniting match?", "answer": "France", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a38c", "question": "What is the second-highest mountain on Earth?", "answer": "K2", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5990f4cffa5fdd6dd25324e6", "question": "Central African Republic shares its northern border with mostly which country?", "answer": "Chad", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ab99b5121a8909e5c332d2a", "question": "Which private investigator tried to find out who framed Roger Rabbit?", "answer": "Eddie Valiant", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c81c", "question": "In what part of the body would you find aqueous humour?", "answer": "The eye", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb46", "question": "Vanilla flavoring is extracted from what part of the vanilla plant?", "answer": "Seed pods", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe6aa1620565ad31a57c810", "question": "Who was the President Kennedy's Secretary of Defense?", "answer": "Robert McNamara", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338928", "question": "Which rock group charted \"Land of Confusion\" in 1986?", "answer": "Genesis", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a840", "question": "The national currency of Panama is named for what Pacific explorer?", "answer": "Balboa", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "601b4af249076251badbeabe", "question": "Ruby Bridges became the first Black student to do what?", "answer": "At six-years-old, Ruby Bridges was the first Black child to be integrated into an all-white school in New Orleans in 1960.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133949e", "question": "Who wrote the novel the miniseries \"Shogun\" was based on?", "answer": "James Clavell", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b63", "question": "What shape is the scar on Harry Potter's forehead?", "answer": "Lightning Bolt", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe1f210145fb29466707396", "question": "What is the Christian holy day falling on the Thursday before Easter?", "answer": "Maundy Thursday or Holy Thursday", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff51d1fff04d658268c9322", "question": "The world's first postage stamp was introduced in what year?", "answer": "The world's first postage stamp, which featured a portrait of Queen Victoria, was introduced by Great Britain in 1840.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ce1", "question": "What term for elaborate, decorative lettering comes from the Greek meaning \"beautiful writing\"?", "answer": "Calligraphy", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a48", "question": "In the TV series, which one of the four main characters on \"Sex and the City\" had a baby?", "answer": "Miranda", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e1e", "question": "What two characters are sculpted on Hannibal, Missouri's Main Street?", "answer": "Tom Sawyer and Huckleberry Finn", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338df6", "question": "What is the Roman name of the Greek god Ares?", "answer": "Mars", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be0f", "question": "Why was Mary Mallon famous in the early 1900s for her signature dessert of peaches and ice cream?", "answer": "It gave people typhus", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c947", "question": "Copper gets its name from which Mediterranean country?", "answer": "Cyprus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338db2", "question": "According to the full title of Richard Wagner's \"Ring Cycle\", the fabulous ring belongs to what race of dwarves?", "answer": "The Nibelung", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe9f3f5ff048f679a45aac5", "question": "What year was the fire extinguisher invented?", "answer": "1723", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe93c096bd93ce3a4e5f6a8", "question": "Which organ cannot feel pain?", "answer": "Brain", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbb4", "question": "In what year did Walt Disney World open near Orlando, Forida?", "answer": "1971", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abb7", "question": "What was Malawi formerly known as?", "answer": "Nyasaland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339352", "question": "How many seasons of the TV show \"The Beverly Hillbillies\" were filmed in black and white?", "answer": "Nine", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe4ddc306d333868d34d708", "question": "In which developed nation was unemployment the highest in the 1920's?", "answer": "Germany", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3e9", "question": "What year did the Republic of South Sudan gain its independence?", "answer": "2011", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff51862ff04d658268c92ff", "question": "What is the most number of years a U.S. president can serve?", "answer": "Ten years -- two years from a previous president's election plus two four-year terms. This is based on the 22nd Amendment.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fea4892ff048f679a45abb0", "question": "How fast can an ostrich run?", "answer": "43 mph", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab0a", "question": "Nuku'alofa is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Tonga", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a909", "question": "What major river runs through Baghdad?", "answer": "Tigris", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca28", "question": "What is the name of the instrument used for listening to the heart?", "answer": "Stethoscope\u00a0", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd9732623c87fd04dd15e56", "question": "Captain Chesley Sullenberger landed a plane in the Hudson River after hitting which animal?", "answer": "Geese", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c131", "question": "In motor racing, what does a yellow flag mean?", "answer": "Caution", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e40", "question": "What's the only consonant sound that can end a word in Japanese?", "answer": "N", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fd96afa23c87fd04dd15e17", "question": "What US president liked to celebrate his birthday by skydiving?", "answer": "George H.W. Bush", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff3c3094f032c0db195b489", "question": "Who was the first European to discover New Zealand?", "answer": "Abel Janszoon Tasman", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a977", "question": "What nation's legislative body is named The Rajya Sabha?", "answer": "India", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c80", "question": "Who was the first musical host of \"Saturday Night Live\"?", "answer": "Sting", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399f7", "question": "What R&B singer was backed by \"The Miracles\"?", "answer": "Smokey Robinson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a833", "question": "Because it entered the union in 1876, what western US state is nicknamed \"The Centennial State\"?", "answer": "Colorado", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58d06d67870e6f05ba600858", "question": "What metals is Bell metal an alloy of?", "answer": "Tin and copper", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5bbd4bc600d154d7af00b8ce", "question": "Which nu metal band released the songs \"My Way\" and \"Rollin'\"?", "answer": "Limp Bizkit", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133934f", "question": "What famous ex-boyfriend of Jennifer Aniston once guest-starred on the TV show \"Friends\"?", "answer": "Brad Pitt", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600241484be4723ccac22174", "question": "What famous author tried to get his wife committed to an insane asylum so he could live with his 18-year-old mistress?", "answer": "Charles Dickens", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c39", "question": "What book won Harper Lee a Pulitzer Prize in 1961?", "answer": "To Kill A Mockingbird", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b52e", "question": "What is the main difference between a Bloody Mary and a Bloody Caeser?", "answer": "Mary is made with Tomato juice and Caesar is made with Clamato juice", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5b32349ebf195a31e15d73a7", "question": "Who played the mermaid Madison in the 1984 film \"Splash\"?", "answer": "Daryl Hannah", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b764", "question": "The name \"Chandler\" literally means what?", "answer": "Candlemaker", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396c9", "question": "The TV show \"Frasier\" is based in what US city?", "answer": "Seattle", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e8c", "question": "What future celebrity made an appearance as Molly in \"Home Alone 3\"?", "answer": "Scarlett Johansson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a37a", "question": "What is the capital of Portugal?", "answer": "Lisbon", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133983a", "question": "Who won a Grammy Award for his album \"Come Dance With Me\"?", "answer": "Frank Sinatra", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c50", "question": "Who rescued Prometheus from the rock to which he was chained?", "answer": "Hercules", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff20e9d31a458464a93c426", "question": "What was Peter Parker's day job?", "answer": "Photographer", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb3f", "question": "How many squares are on a checker board?", "answer": "64", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa16", "question": "What is the Capital of Guadeloupe?", "answer": "Basse-Terre", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b48a", "question": "Which country were the 1992 Summer Olympic Games held in?", "answer": "Spain", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133928d", "question": "What title was the movie \"Evil Dead III\" released under?", "answer": "Army of Darkness", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133accb", "question": "What color suits are associated with Japanese Ninja?", "answer": "Black", "category": "history"}, {"id": "590721db3745b36be73039fa", "question": "Which Disney character is named after Ebenezer from Charles Dickens\u2019 novel \"A Christmas Carol\"?", "answer": "Scrooge McDuck", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5937ede908d98002fdd633cd", "question": "In which city is the C.N. Tower?", "answer": "Toronto", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5a162a64f01ec323f8491723", "question": "What carries sensations from the tongue to the brain?", "answer": "Lingual nerve", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398c8", "question": "What instrument was Jelly Roll Morton best known for playing?", "answer": "Piano", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fede3946ce05a3942286dd4", "question": "Robert De Niro auditioned for which character in the film \"The Godfather\"?", "answer": "Sonny", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7bf10877e98cb97778965", "question": "What is the smallest country in South America?", "answer": "Suriname", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5b32362bbf195a31e15d73b8", "question": "What year was the character of Betty Crocker first introduced?", "answer": "1921", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c280", "question": "What abbreviation comes from libra, meaning pound in Latin?", "answer": "lb", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a1e", "question": "What city was the setting for the TV show \"Perfect Strangers\"?", "answer": "Chicago", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffcfaed9dc5ec6cd98a8313", "question": "What does Italian artist Maurizio Savini make sculptures out of?", "answer": "Chewing gum -- He aims to remember childhood and personal memories by sculpting\u00a0pink chewing gum\u00a0and fiberglass.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fecc0a8ec223966ae8f885d", "question": "What guards the Ark of the Covenant in \"Raiders of the Lost Ark\"?", "answer": "Snakes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58e2f5602e77afa695b03105", "question": "Mal\u00e9 is the capital of which Asian country?", "answer": "Maldives", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fea7a04ff048f679a45abe5", "question": "Where is the uvula located?", "answer": "In the throat", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6018bd8bd96d05b23b28165c", "question": "Atropos, Lachesis, and Clotho are the Three what of Greek mythology?", "answer": "Fates", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c987", "question": "What animal has the highest blood pressure?", "answer": "Giraffe", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388cd", "question": "One of Oscar Wilde's best-known works is a play titled \"The Importance of Being ...\"what?", "answer": "Earnest", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4c3", "question": "What name is given to the unit of electrical resistance?", "answer": "Ohm", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a003", "question": "What British TV series featured David Brent and Gareth Keenan?", "answer": "The Office", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133939e", "question": "Which 1993 movie is subtitled: \"The Bruce Lee Story\"?", "answer": "Dragon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600f6ed4a9e54d890926f6cb", "question": "Which American city was home to the world's first skyscraper?", "answer": "Chicago -- The Home Insurance Building was 180 ft. tall.  Constructed in 1885, it was demolished in 1931.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7e0", "question": "Which US state is home to both the highest and lowest points in the contiguous 48 US states?", "answer": "California", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398da", "question": "What TV series starred trail hands Gil Favor and Rowdy Yates?", "answer": "Rawhide", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5937ef0108d98002fdd633dc", "question": "What is a person with numerophobia afraid of?", "answer": "Numbers or mathematics", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cd1", "question": "What is the shortest and bloodiest of Shakespeare's plays?", "answer": "Macbeth", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395d5", "question": "In The Simpsons, what is the name of Springfield's video arcade?", "answer": "Noiseland", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133caed", "question": "Prometheus is an inner satellite of which planet?", "answer": "Saturn", "category": "science"}]